so let's discuss some examples of vliw
processor the most famous example of how
to probably not do vliw is Intel
xitanium processors it had tons of Isa
features that help the compiler schedule
code well Etc as a result the hardware
of the processor became very complicated
it no longer needed to check for
dependencies between instructions but it
had so many other bells and whistles to
do this that the hardware is probably
the most complicated Intel ever built
and and yet fundamentally this is still
a vliw processor so it's still not doing
great on irregular code another example
of where vliw is often used is DSP
processors where DSP stands for digital
signal processing Digital Signal
processing does a lot of floating Point
work typically in a very regular group
with a very small amount of work within
each iteration and lots of lots of
iterations so typically these types of
processors on these types of codes get
excellent performance and are also Al
very energy efficient because they don't
spend much power on figuring out
dependencies and so on so these are
examples of when we try to use VW for
all types of codes we run into problems
but if we find a type of codes where
compilers can do well suddenly VW looks
like a very very good choice for that